Finding Aid for G.M. (Gerard M.) Faeth papers, 1964-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Presentations, Publications, and Reviews 1985-2005, undated
  - 2004
    - Fire Prevention, Detection, and Suppression June 22-23, 2004 (Box 10)
    - Formation and Oxidation of Primary Soot Particles in Flames January 2004 (Box 10)
    - Mechanisms of Soot Formation and Oxidation in Laminar Flames December 15-17, 2004 (Box 10)
    - Nucleation, Growth and Oxidation of TEM-Observable Primary Soot Particles March 29-30, 2004 (Box 10)
    - Primary Breakup of Aerated Liquid Jets in Uniform Gaseous Crossflows September 6-8, 2004 (Box 10)
    - Reaction Properties of TEM-Observable Primary Soot Particles in Flame Environments, October 4-8 2004 (Box 10)
    - Self-Preserving Mixing Properties of Steady Round Non-buoyant Turbulent Jets in Uniform Crossflows July 11-15, 2004 (Box 10)
    - Soot Surfaces Growth and Oxidation in Laminar Diffusion Flames at Pressures of 0.1-1.0 ATM 2004 (Box 10)
  - 2005
    - Plif and Piv Measurements of the Self-Preserving Structure of Steady Round Buoyant Turbulent Plumes in Crossflow April 17-21, 2005 (Box 10)
    - Primary and Secondary Breakup of Sprays January 28, 2005 (Box 10)
    - Primary Breakup of Round Turbulent Liquid Jets in Uniform Crossflows January 10-13, 2005 (Box 10)
    - Reaction Properties of Primary Soot Particles in Flames: Effects of Aromatic Fuels and Sub-Atmospheric Pressures March 21-23, 2005 (Box 10)
    - Search for the Mechanisms of Pollutant Soot Formation and Destruction in Flames, Distinguished University Professorship Lecture (not given) February 8, 2005 (Box 10)
    - Self-Preserving Mixing Properties of Steady Round Buoyant Turbulent Plumes in Uniform Crossflows June 19-23, 2005 (Box 10)
    - Weakly-Buoyant Turbulent Fire Plumes in Uniform Still and Crossflowing Environments, Proposed Chapter for Transport Phenomena in Fires (includes photos) circa 2005 (Box 10)
  - Combustion and Flame Publishing 2002, 2005
    - Bids and Proposal for Combustion and Flame Publishing Contract 2002 (Box 10)
    - Publisher's Review 2005 (Box 10)
  - Presentation Outlines 1988-2003 (Box 10)
  - Proposal Reviews 2001-2004
    - 2001-2002 (Box 10)
    - 2003, 3 folders (Box 10)
    - 2004 (Box 10)
- Visual Materials 1964-2004, undated
  Visual Materials, 1964-2004 (2.5 linear feet) with bulk dates from 1980-2004, contains visual materials divided in two sub-series: Photographs; and DVDs and VHS Videotapes. Photographs includes images of experimental runs and apparatus. Of particular note are Faeth's thesis and Navy research photographs, photographs taken within the NASA Space Shuttle during the Laminar Soot Processes (LSP) experiment, as well as a large conceptual drawing for the Sooting Flames Experiment # 7 Combustion Module I aboard the Space Station Freedom. DVDs and VHS Videotapes contains footage of live experimental runs of flames at various measurements, both with and without audio, space shuttle footage, both inside the shuttle and at takeoff, as well as footage of various experimental equipment. Of particular note are the VHS videotapes focusing on the Laminar Soot Processes Experiment (LSP), which record live footage of the performance of data collection for the Laminar Soot Processes in Space Shuttle Columbia Flights STS 83 and 94, and other related experimental runs.
  - Photographs 1964-2004, undated
    - General
      - Combustion Module-2 Foam Core Logo Display undated (Box 10)
      - Thesis and Navy Research Photographs, (experimental apparatus) circa 1964 (Box 10)
      - KL-135 Houston Takeoff, circa 1999 (Box 10)
      - Sooting Flames-Experiment # 7 Combustion Module -- 1 for Space Station Freedom, (conceptual drawing) 1992 (Box 10)
      - Various Photographs (includes photographs of laboratories, soot, plumes, and slides) undated (Box 10)
    - Experimental Runs
      - Dai and Faeth Paper undated (Box 10)
      - Grid Post undated (Box 10)
      - Laminar Soot Processes (LSP) Experiment (includes projectors slides, a 3.5 inch floppy disc with text for slides, video prints, and NASA Shuttle photographs) circa 1997, 1 floppy disk 3.5"; 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Multi-Facility Comparison of LSP Flames 1986-1997 (Box 11)
      - Negatives of Experimental Film Runs undated (Box 12)
      - Sejin Kwon Runs, Office of Naval Research undated (Box 12)
      - Spray Runs, Office of Naval Research undated (Box 12)
      - STS-83/03E and 01E (black and white) undated (Box 12)
      - STS-94 undated (Box 12)
      - STS-94 SOFBALL and LSP in USML-1 July 1997, 3 folders (Box 12)
      - STS-94 Repeats of Ethylene 1.6 mm, (includes projector slides), circa early 1980s, 2004 (Box 12)
  - DVDs and Videotape 1991-1997, undated
    - #1. [Optical Equipment], undated, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #2. CM1 Laminar Soot Processes (LSP) Flames September 11, 1995, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #3. Copy of Hitachi Color Camera Test (LM-1 LSP), undated, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #4. Ethylene Flames Filtered at 431.5 nm Using 1 nm Bond Pass Filters, NASA LERC August 15, 1991, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #5. LSP MSL-1, 4 Camera Views, circa 1997, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #6. LSP Color Video, Flames 1 and 2, C2H4 1 and 1/2 atm April 4, 1997, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #7. LSP SLF, Butane Lighter in SUF Image With and Without the Laser July 30, 1996, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #8. LSP STS-83 and 94, undated, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #8. LSP in STS-83 and 94 (LSP Operations on Board STS-83/94, April and July 1997, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
  - DVDs and Videotape 1991-1997, undated
    - #9. LSP STS-83 TP 01E and 03E with Titles, undated, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #10. LSP STS-94, Color Flame Images Copied from Hi-Pac Tape, July 9 (no year given), VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #11. LSP2 Video 4E May 30, 2003, DVD (Box 13)
    - #12. Miscellaneous Propane Gas Jet Experiments on KC-135 March 3, 1992, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #13. NASA Lewis Research Center MSL-1/CM-1, STS-94 LSP, Flight Video Tape, undated, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #14. Optical Microscope Views of STS-83 Soot Paddles and TEM Grids, undated, VHS Videotape (Box 13)
    - #15. STS-94 Duplicated 06E, undated, VHS Videotape